SRINIVAS PRASAD AKELLA

Bengaluru, Karnataka, 560068 | 7995643201

srinivas72075@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/srinivas-prasad-akella-6abb28195

Software professional with a total of 2+ years experience in MERN stack web development, testing and debugging websites using trending web-technologies - React JS, Node JS, ExpressJS, Next Js, Redux, Python, etc... Additionally, I have experience working on databases - MongoDB, MYSQL and such technologies. Currently upskilling with React Native. Interested in emerging as a solution provider for complex IT related business problems leveraging the skills of a Software Application.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web React Developer, Appening Infotech Pvt Ltd.

June 2024 - present

- Developing and debugging the web pages with logics and good looking UI for the latest trendy applications which are provided to B2B & B2C organizations.
- Using github to maintain code and collaborate with the team for work updates.
- Learning the new and latest libraries like redux saga and redux toolkit query by doing.

Freelancing Feb 2024 - May 2024

- Training Employees for NextJS and ReactJS.
- Developing UI for some websites and debugging existing websites

Full-stack Mentor/Developer, Aroha Technologies

July 2023 - Jan 2024

- Training students and fresher candidates to upskill in popular web technologies such as ReactJs, NodeJs, MongoDB, ExpressJs, MySQL, Postgres, SQLite.
- Building beautiful & user friendly interfaces and related documentation as part of training

Associate Software Engineer, Teknotrait Solution Pvt. Ltd.

Dec 2021 - May 2023

- Developing static, dynamic pages using React Js, MUI and third party libraries.
- Styling the websites with css libraries like styled-components, sass, MUI and normal css.
- Integrating the web api's with **Redux**, dispatching **actions** in components and using their global states in the components from **reducers**.
- Hosting sites on Hostinger, on-render and AWS.
- Building various projects for training Interns regarding HTML, CSS, JS and MERN stack.

EDUCATION

B.Com, Computers

May 2015 - Apr 2018

Aditya Degree College, East Godavari, Andhra Pradesh CGPA - [7.36]

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, MUI
- NodeJs, ExpressJs, ReactJs, Redux
- BitBucket, Github

- JavaScript, TypeScript, NextJs
- MongoDB, mySQL, SQLite
- Python, flask, React Native

CERTIFICATIONS

CCBP Intensive 4.0 Tech Program (Certificate Link)

Mar 2021 - May 2021

NxtWave Disruptive Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

(Industry Ready Certification program focused on MERN stack web development that provides rigorous training with immersive hands-on, in trending web technologies - Node Js, React Js, javaScript, Github...)

PROJECTS

Food Ordering App(Project Link)

Dec 2023

Technologies: MaterialUI, CSS Flexbox, ReactJs, NodeJs, MongoDB, ExpressJs, Redux core

A food ordering application with two roles- restaurant owner and user, where a restaurant owner can do crud operations on restaurants and food items and a user can add food items to cart and place order. Integrated Payment Gateway too. And also I have implemented theming.

Hotel Booking App(Project Link)

Apr 2023

Technologies: MaterialUI, ReactJs, NodeJs, MongoDB, Express, Redux core

A hotel booking application with two roles - admin for creating the hotels in particular cities and customer to book the rooms in hotels. I was more into logical implementation during this project.

NxtTrends (Project Link)

Aug 2022

Technologies: HTML, CSS, CSS Flexbox, ReactJs

A responsive website for doing online shopping, only client side.

[Username - rahul, Password - rahul@2021]

Emoji Game (Project Link)

Oct 2022

Technologies: HTML, CSS, CSS Flexbox, ReactJs

A simple stress-buster game where a user plays with emojis and scores points. Here you have to select different emoji each time the page renders.

Portfolio(Project Link)

Jan 2024

Technologies: HTML, CSS, CSS Flexbox, NextJS

I have built a portfolio with NextJS and even you can contact me through mail. This is like my visual Resume with my skills, projects, work and all.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Developing Portfolio full stack projects

Teaching Friends on the concepts of web Development